[{"id":"4498","question":"<p>Successive discounts of 10% and 30% are equivalent to a single&nbsp; discount of:&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"40%","option2":"35%","option3":"38%  ","option4":"37% ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"37% ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:45:03","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Equivalent discount<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>30 + 10 -&nbsp;<sup>30 &times; 10<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;= 37 %<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"4491","question":"<p>A motor starts with the speed of 70 kmph with its speed increasing every two hours by 10 kmph. In how many hours will it cover 345 kms?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"2<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>4<\/sub>  hours","option2":"4 <sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>2<\/sub>  hours","option3":"4 hours 5 minutes","option4":"Cannot be determined","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"4 <sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>2<\/sub>  hours","qa_date":"2015-11-06 18:56:22","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Initial speed of motor = 70 kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Distance covered I first two hours = 2 &times; 70 = 140 kms<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">For next two hours speed of motor = 80 kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Distance covered in next 2 hours = 2 &times; 80 = 160 kms<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Distance covered in first four hours = 140m+ 160= 300<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Remaining distance = 345 &ndash; 300 = 45 km<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">The distance will be covered at the speed of 90 kmph<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Time taken = &nbsp;<sup>45<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>90<\/sub>&nbsp;= &nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp; hour<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Total time<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">= 4 + &nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>&nbsp;= 4<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>2<\/sub>hours<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"4499","question":"<p>The average age of 30 boys in a class is 15 years. One boy aged 20 years, left the class, but two new boys come in his place whose age differs by five years. If the average age of all the boys now in the class becomes 15 years, the age of the younger new comer is:<\/p>\r\n","option1":"20 years","option2":"15 years      ","option3":"10 years   ","option4":"8 years","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"15 years      ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:47:16","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"4500","question":"<p>A train running at&nbsp;<span style=\"font-size:14px\"><sup>7<\/sup>&frasl;<\/span><sub><span style=\"font-size:12px\">11<\/span><span style=\"font-size:14px\">&nbsp;<\/span><span style=\"font-size:12px\">of its own speed reached a place in 22 hours. How much time could be saved if the train would run at its own speed?<\/span><\/sub><\/p>\r\n","option1":"14 hours  ","option2":"7 hours","option3":"8 hours","option4":"16 hours","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"8 hours","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:49:54","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"4493","question":"<p>If a man walks 20 km at 5 km per hr, he will be late by 40 minutes. If he walks at 8 km per hr, how early from the fixed time will he reach?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"15 minutes   ","option2":"25 minutes   ","option3":"50 minutes ","option4":"1<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>2<\/sub> hours ","option5":"None of these  ","correct_option":"50 minutes ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:39:53","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Time taken to cover 20 km at the speed of 5 km\/hr<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 4 hours<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Fixed time<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 4 hours &ndash; 40 minutes<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 3 hours 20 minutes<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Time taken to cover 20 km at the speed of 8 km\/hr &nbsp;<sup>20<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 2 hours 30 minutes<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required time = 3 hours 20 minutes &ndash; 2 hours 3o minutes = 50 minutes<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"4494","question":"<p>By selling article for Rs. 240 a man incurs a loss of 10%. At what price should he sell it. so that he makes a profit of 20%?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 264   ","option2":"Rs. 288 ","option3":"Rs. 300  ","option4":"Rs. 320   ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Rs. 320   ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:39:53","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>90% of C.P. = Rs. 240<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>C.P. = Rs.&nbsp;<sup>240 &times; 100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>90<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>New S.P = 120% of C.P.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. 240 &times;<sup>100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>90<\/sub>&times;<sup>120<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. 320<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"4497","question":"<p>The average income of 40% person is Rs.4200 and that of another 35 persons is Rs.4000. The average income of the whole group is: &nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs.41100  ","option2":"Rs.4106<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>3<\/sub>   ","option3":"Rs.4106<sup>2<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>3<\/sub>     ","option4":"Rs.4108<sup>1<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>3<\/sub>    ","option5":"None of these  ","correct_option":"Rs.4106<sup>2<\/sup>\u00e2\u0081\u201e<sub>3<\/sub>     ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:45:03","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Average age of whole group<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>4200&times;40+4000&times;35<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>75<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>168000+140000<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>75<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp;<sup>308000<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>75<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 4106<sup>2<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>3<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<div>&nbsp;<\/div>\r\n"},{"id":"4492","question":"<p>Four bells ring at intervals of 4, 6, 8, and 14 seconds. They start ringing simultaneously at 12.00 O&#39; clock; at what time will they again ring simultaneously?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"12 hrs. 2 min. 48 sec.","option2":"12 hrs. 3 min.    ","option3":"12 hrs. 3 min. 20 sec.   ","option4":"12 hrs. 3 min. 44 sec. ","option5":"None of these  ","correct_option":"12 hrs. 2 min. 48 sec.","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:33:04","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>LCM of 4 , 6, 8, 14<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 168 seconds<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 2 minutes , 45 seconds<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>They ring again at 12 + 2 min. 48 sec.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= 12 hrs. 2 min. 48 sec.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"4495","question":"<p>What some of money must be given at simple interest for six months at 4% per annum in order to earn Rs. 150 interest?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 5000   ","option2":"Rs. 7500   ","option3":"Rs. 10000   ","option4":"Rs. 15000  ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Rs. 7500   ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:39:53","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>P =&nbsp;<sup>150 &times; 100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4<\/sub>&times;<sup>2<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>1<\/sub>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>=&nbsp; Rs. 7500<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"4496","question":"<p>Divide Rs. 1250 among A, B, C, so that&rsquo;s A gets 2\/9 of B&#39;s share and C gets 3\/4 of A&#39;s share.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 200, Rs. 900, Rs. 250   ","option2":"Rs.200, Rs.900, Rs.150.   ","option3":"Rs.150, Rs.800, Rs.300.  ","option4":"Rs.200, Rs.900, Rs.75 ","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"Rs.200, Rs.900, Rs.75 ","qa_date":"2015-11-06 20:45:03","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>A = B &times;&nbsp;<sup>2<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>9<\/sub>&nbsp;=&nbsp;<sup>2B<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>9<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>C =&nbsp;<sup>3A<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4<\/sub>&nbsp;A =&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>3<\/sub>C<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Ratio of A: B : C = 4 : 18 : 3<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Share of A =&nbsp;<sup>4<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>25<\/sub>&times; 1250 = Rs. 200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Share of B =&nbsp;<sup>18<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>25<\/sub>&nbsp;&times; 1250 = Rs. 900<\/p>\r\n"}]